<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Presentations on Foldable Robotics Camp</title><link>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/</link><description>Recent content in Presentations on Foldable Robotics Camp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Biomechanics and Bioinspiration</title><link>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/biomechanics-and-bioinspiration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/biomechanics-and-bioinspiration/</guid><description>After Lunch Plan Origami Wrapup - More Mechanisms Biomechanics &amp;amp; Bioinspiration continue identifying important keywords and putting them in padlet Look up an animal look up keywords in google scholar Make a 1-slide presentation / proposal what motion do you want to find a video of it moving what information did you find on it? What’s your idea for how to make it “foldable”? Form Teams Make a body module. Bio-Inspiration Robotic Systems help us understand the biological world Can mimic biological structures Experiments can be designed and repeated vs.</description></item><item><title>ESP32 and MicroPython</title><link>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/esp32-and-micropython/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/esp32-and-micropython/</guid><description>Welcome Group Padlet Link HERE Presentation Folder Vocab Review from Yesterday! Go to our Kahoot Game! https://play.kahoot.it/v2/?quizId=b9e3cfc4-d2fe-4c3f-adad-e9f343f837cd Overview of the ESP32 DevKit DOIT V1 Pinouts / Schematics from https://randomnerdtutorials.com/getting-started-with-esp32/ Board Layout Mount your ESP32 on your Breadboard ESP32 Links Espressif ESP32-WROOM-32 Datasheet ESP32-Devkit-C Page Devkit Technical Documents External Pinout Resources https://johnmu.com/picking-esp32-dev-board/ https://www.etechnophiles.com/esp32-dev-board-pinout-specifications-datasheet-and-schematic/ https://www.studiopieters.nl/esp32-pinout/ MicroPython Intro What is Python? Easy to learn programming language
Interpreted Language - write code and have it execute without compiling!</description></item><item><title>Final Build Day</title><link>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/final-build-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/final-build-day/</guid><description>To-Do Consider Adding Advanced WiFi Control Sensing Time-based functions (sinusoid function) Vinyl-Cut Parts …other ideas? Camp is Over. Now What? Consider joining or starting a robotics club at your school Vex Robotics First Robotics Take your kit home, continue learning I will provide the parts list if you want to expand or re-order parts Today’s Schedule 9-11:45 Final Build Session 11:45-12:45 Lunch &amp;amp; Mixer 1-1:30 Innovation Hub Tour 1:30-2:00 Final Documentation 2:00-2:30 Cleanup 2:30-3:00 Internal Presentations 3-4 Showcase!</description></item><item><title>Foldable Mechanisms</title><link>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/foldable-mechanisms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/foldable-mechanisms/</guid><description>Keywords Mechanism Linkage Link Joint Degrees of Freedom Why are we talking about foldable mechanisms? Robots are mechanisms, or machines. Serial vs. Parallel Composed of links and joints Mechanisms A system of parts working together in a machine; a piece of machinery.
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mechanism_(engineering)
https://languages.oup.com/google-dictionary-en/
Structures? What is a structure? Linkage A system of links; especially a system of links or bars which are jointed together and more or less constrained by having a link or links fixed and by means of which straight or nearly straight lines or other point paths may be traced</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/introduction/</guid><description>Welcome to Foldable Robotics Day Camp Daniel M. Aukes, PhD Assistant Professor here at ASU Teach classes related to robotics, engineering, and embedded systems You can call me Dr. Aukes or Dan Research Foldable Robotics and other “informal” robot design methods I will try to talk a little about my research at the end of the week Please let me know if you don’t understand what I am saying…I’m an expert, I can’t help it!</description></item><item><title>RC Servos</title><link>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/rc-servos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-camp/presentations/rc-servos/</guid><description>What is an RC Servo Not just a motor, an “Electromechanical System” What’s inside https://www.sparkfun.com/servos Common Servo Sizes How do you plug in a Servo? Three wires: Ground - usually black Power - usually red Signal - neither red nor black Other Kinds of Servos Linear Servos: Same idea, only you use a lead screw to translate the output rather than rotate Continuous Rotation Servos: The potentiometer is removed, so the control signal just relates to speed Servos with Feedback: Extra wire for position value Servo Mounting Ideas Controlling a Servo PWM: Pulse Width Modulation The “value” sent by a PWM signal is the proportion of the time on vs the “period”, or time between signals frequency = 1/period period = 200ms frequency = ?</description></item></channel></rss>